It won't open.
We must escape before we reach the fields.
Isabel?
If they've taken the book and with it our powers,
what would you have me do?
Anything. We're running out of time.
Time is the one thing we do have.
If we fall this night, I promise you,
we will rise again to finish our quest.
I promise.
Keep moving. Keep moving.
Magistrate Wilkins.
Come to enjoy your handiwork?
Tell me of the three stones of power, Countess.
You may yet escape the pyre's flames.
My book.
There's a page marked.
What means this?
It means that the stones of power shall be mine.
And once I possess them, you shall tremble at my feet
and never again persecute my kind.
Animan Remito.
Demon.
Join your confederates.
Please.
Have mercy.
No. No, please.
Madeline Ebeneez.
Brianna Witherspoon.
The witch.
Countess Marguerite Isabel Thoreau.
You have been found guilty of committing the darkest art, witchcraft.
With this affront against God,
I hereby condemn you to burn in the fires of hell
of which you so eagerly seek communion.
No.
You think this ends with a lick of flame?
Yeah.
I sleep but a while.
And when the time is appointed, my heir will awaken me,
And I will have vengeance!
No!
Oh!
Yeah!
No!
Oh!
So you found it on eBay.
Yeah, this old guy, Anise, was auctioning it off.
I had to max out my entire credit card to get it,
but I couldn't resist. It was like it was calling to me.
The spellbook of Countess Isabelle Margaret Thoreau.
Oh.
Those look like the same symbols in the cave.
Yeah.
Maybe it'll help explain what happened in Paris
when I touched Isabelle's tomb.
Yeah, and the tattoo and the missing 12 hours.
So, uh, how's your Latin?
Not as good as my Italian, which I don't speak.
I'll get it.
Oh, my God.
What?
This is the symbol from Isabelle's tomb.
That's kind of spooky.
What?
Whoa.
You okay?
Never been better.
I'm sorry.
Hey, Lois, what are you doing here?
Why aren't you at school?
We're having a surprise party for Chloe's 18th birthday in your barn, remember?
No. I remember telling you you couldn't have it here.
Too late now.
Everyone's already been invited.
And you really don't want it getting back to Chloe that you rained on her shindig.
That would hurt her feelings.
What?
And I'd have to hurt you.
Listen, Lois, I don't want to...
Would you get me a hundred thieves?
I have to get the wheels back to my dad before he notices they're missing.
Lois, we can't do this tonight.
The guy from prison's coming to meet me.
He's in town.
Relax, Smallville.
It's just gonna be a couple of people standing around singing happy birthday.
It's not gonna be Sodom and Gomorrah.
Mr. Ivy League won't even know we're here.
Trust me.
Hair of two virgins.
We've been a good little girl, haven't we?
Hello?
Oh, you are home. I've been calling, but no one answered.
Well, I've been kind of preoccupied.
Science project.
From what century?
It's a whole retro thing.
Trying to recreate some of the stuff they did back in the 1600s.
Oh.
I really think you two are going to like it.
Damn, I left my phone in your car. Do you mind?
Oh, no. No worries.
This whole smell of science is making me crave an aromatic latte anyway, so...
I'll just meet you downstairs with your cell phone.
Bye.
Bye. Thanks.
What's the matter with you?
You were supposed to take Chloe shopping so that I could finish everything with the party?
Right. Must have slipped my mind.
Right. Must have slipped my mind. Wow.
Get some traction. Little misreporter there?
She can smell a ruse a mile away.
I'm going to need some serious help to keep her from ferreting out whatever it is we're planning tonight.
Ow!
Oh, no.
Now that's no good.
Well, yeah, not since you pulled it out.
It was gray.
I don't have gray hair.
I'm just going to use your bathroom for a second.
Maybe you need a woman's touch.
Hey, Lana.
Hello, Clark.
It's a big box.
It's a gift for Chloe.
Lois and I got it for her.
I'm sure that she'll love it.
Especially if it's from you.
Look, I'm glad you're here.
I wanted to talk to you about what happened with Jason.
Oh, don't worry about it.
It's water under a very tall bridge.
Are you feeling okay?
You seem a little low on...
Different.
Maybe it's the company.
Jason's my friend.
Well, he doesn't think so.
Hey, what's...
What are you doing?
I need a lock of your hair for a scrapbook
I need a lock of your hair for a scrapbook for Chloe's birthday.
All you had to do was ask.
Well, where's the fun in that?
What happened to these?
They were broken already.
Here, is that enough?
It's perfect.
Thanks, handsome.
You're welcome.
I'm going to check that box.
Can you find it?
You can find it.
I see it.
It's perfect.
You play beautifully.
Thanks, but I'm afraid I'm a little rusty.
Well, I hate to interrupt,
but I wanted to ask you for a favor.
Have I ever been able to refuse Lana Lang?
What do you need?
Oh, a good bottle of wine for Chloe's birthday.
Well, the last time I checked, she wasn't turning 21 yet.
I know, but I thought it'd be nice to raise a glass
with her and Lois to celebrate.
I promise I won't tell anyone where I got it from.
It'll be our little secret.
Well, I think I might have a light Riesling
that won't do too much damage.
Actually, I was looking more for a vintage Merlot
from the south of France.
Something from a vineyard in the Languedoc
or possibly the Dordogne.
That should do enough.
You want a pinch?
Your taste has certainly matured from a summer in Paris.
Just give me a second.
1902 from the Salier Vineyards in Languedoc.
Should make quite the birthday present.
What is this?
Just a little something I picked up in St. Petersburg.
It's an illuminated manuscript
depicting the ancient...
You're lying.
What?
You know it's true nature,
but the map was not meant for you.
Lana, how did you know there's a map hidden under the page?
Because...
Vanessa!
Lana, what did you do?
Phoenix!
You seek the stones, don't you?
Well, we can't have that.
I think that you're right, Alexander.
You do need more practice.
Keep playing.
Infinitas.
ucha.
I said了吧 about the sea,
and this was the last of the wills,
Per luna met mare, rede erque sublate sunt.
Per luna met mare, rede erque sublate...
Okay, what are we doing in the woods?
Chloe's right behind me in the Moonlight Nature Hike.
It's making her a little suspicious.
I thought it'd be nice to get together with my girls before the party.
What party?
Way to ruin the surprise.
Oh, you mean the party that you've been planning for the last month?
You know about that?
Oh, hello, investigative reporter.
Nothing gets past me.
Except why we're playing wood nymph when there's a party waiting for me with my name on it.
Then we'd better hurry.
A toast.
In honor of this special night.
All right.
This is getting better.
No matter how much time passes, old friends are never forgotten.
Drink to that.
Cheers.
Madeline?
Brianna?
Welcome to the 21st century.
How did we come to be here?
The last spell I cast before Wilkins condemned me to the pyre.
My blood entwined with the symbol in the book which called to my heir.
And my blood was blood.
And when she touched it, I gained possession of her body
and brought you back.
I'm gorgeous.
Look at these.
Yes, they're very nice.
Ah, the woods of France.
I'd know them anywhere.
We're in Kansas, Madeline.
Where?
The Americas.
I am unsure as to why I was resurrected here.
It was not of my intention, but.
The book. Do you have it?
It is ours once again.
And with it, our magics.
Now we may continue our quest for the stone.
Oh, uh, is that the same quest that got us burnt at the stake?
That was not pleasant.
A small toll to travel the road of ultimate power.
You have your host, Madeline.
I'm sure you have memories.
Use them to navigate this world and help us to seize the power.
Oh.
All right.
Look, Chase, Clarke, I'm only here because Lana wants me to be here,
because I'm her boyfriend, whether you like it or not.
We don't have time for this.
Time is the only thing we do have.
Isn't that what you said right before the angry mob set us on fire?
You're really not gonna let that go, are you?
The guy from Princeton's gonna be here any minute.
Why are you so late?
I took the scenic route.
Love the view.
Have you been drinking?
Hey, so, I don't want to be rude,
but I think I'm just gonna tell Chloe happy birthday and take off.
Well, you're a big boy. You can do what you want.
Well, you're the one who wanted me here.
Well, things change.
Why are you acting like this?
And why are you dressed like that?
Because it makes me feel sexy.
Aren't you leaving?
I am.
The food is so good in this century.
And the men actually bathe.
And the bodies are so hard.
But we have definitely had better celebrations.
This is appalling.
We could change that.
Well, it has been 400 years.
That's a little fun, before we continue our quest.
Quiz!
She said yes to all theOOuy answers.
I am the val device Alice asked me to answer in his paper.
murder.
Party.
We gotright to нуwhat?
kuchen.
What if they say that you're a clever
Not sure what I'm doing
Who really cares cause it's your life
You never know if you'd be brave
Take a chance cause you might fail
A worse heart can't be
Hard
Mr. Jacobs, Princeton University
Hey, come on in, join the party!
Woo!
Hey, Mom!
Yeah, how's Metropolis?
Really, I'm glad you're having a great time!
Wait, wait, wait, come on in!
What?
Oh, yeah, the guy from Princeton.
Um, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
Yeah, I met him last night.
I, um, don't worry.
I think I made an impression.
Lex, can I talk to you for a second?
I got a big problem.
I was supposed to meet this alumni from Princeton last night.
But then Lois wanted to throw a party for Chloe in the barn.
Well, the party kind of got out of hand.
Then the guy from Princeton showed up and I think I kind of blew it.
Look, um, I hate to say this, but I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
I hate to ask you this, but do you have any connections at Princeton?
Lex?
Lex, what are you doing?
Stop.
Stop it.
You can't.
Stop.
Lex, what happened?
Lana.
You really shouldn't play with that.
You might hurt yourself.
I heard you and the girls were the life of the party last night.
One last fling before I finish what I started a long time ago.
No.
You don't want to get in my way.
Who are you?
Qui est-ce que vous pensez?
Isabel?
In the new flesh.
What did you do with Lana?
She's in here somewhere.
Could you let her out?
Now why on earth would I let her go?
What a witch you are.
You're so mean.
What's wrong with you?
I'm not mean.
You're so mean.
What's wrong with you?
I'm just saying that I love you.
I love you.
Now why on earth would I love you?
You're so mean.
So mean.
You can't ask me that.
No, I can't.
I can't.
Now why on earth would I ever do that?
You know, all this started when Lana found this book.
So I'm guessing if anything happens to this book...
You have no idea what you're dealing with, little man.
Vaculate!
So assume.
So now you begin to understand.
You are not but an insect in my path.
To be crushed on the journey toward greater things.
Lana, no!
Jason, are you okay?
No.
You're early.
Not planning something devious, are you, Clark?
What did you do to Lex and Jason?
Nothing compared to what we're going to do.
What are you going to do to you?
Surge, okay?
I don't know what's going on, but this needs to stop.
Before it gets out of hand.
So you're more than just fast.
Well, that'll make this a whole lot more exciting.
I don't want to hurt anyone.
Your magics are impressive.
Magic?
Magic.
But so are mine.
Ever say.
We have traveled through the ages to complete our quest.
Outwitting death itself.
We will not be undone by some farm boy with a few tricks.
He's not what he seems, Isabel.
I can feel his power.
Remember, have a drink.
I guess we should rid him of it.
Chloe, you gotta help.
I know you're in there.
Clark?
Listen to me.
You gotta help me.
.
The End
He awakens.
What have you done to me?
We made sure you were no longer a threat, Sorcerer.
I'm not a sorcerer.
You're not?
Are you sure?
No.
He's something else.
Something special.
I could sense it when your magics were ripped from your body.
I can taste it on you.
No.
The Three Stones of Power.
You know of them, don't you?
I've never heard of them.
You've done more than hear them.
You've touched them.
We can feel it.
There's more.
You know where one of them is hidden.
Tell us where it is, Clark.
Please tell us.
I don't know what you're talking about.
No.
There are easier ways to get what we want.
This body I inhabit.
You have desires for it, don't you?
Well, it desires you too, Clark.
Very,
very much.
Monster.
The game.
Thank you, Clark.
You've been very helpful.
I'll be back.
Clark?
Are you all right?
What happened?
Did Lana do this to you?
Take it easy. Take it easy.
Where is she? I need to find her.
She's with Lois and Chloe, but they're different.
They're not themselves. It's like their bodies have been taken over.
They have. In fact, this is gonna sound kinda out there.
Let's get you out of here.
Lana has been researching a 17th century witch.
She tracked down her spell book,
and when she touched her hand to the page...
Wait a second. Lana's been possessed by the spirit of an evil witch?
Yes.
The spell got into Lana by using the book.
So we gotta find her and destroy the book.
Any idea where they went?
I'm not sure.
Why don't you check the school?
I'll go to the Talon.
All right.
Clark, call myself.
Find them, okay? Don't try anything alone.
Just be careful, okay?
Begins to make sense.
Why I was resurrected here in this time,
a thousand leagues from my home.
It was destiny.
Can you feel it?
Calling to us.
The first stone of power lies behind this wall.
And with it,
our magic shall increase tenfold.
And when we possess all the stones,
we shall walk on earth again.
we shall walk on earth as gods among men.
Reach out
and seize what was meant to be.
Muroskindandum!
Voluntas victora nostra est.
All of our suffering,
all of our pain and persecution,
it ends tonight.
And our future begins.
Take it, Isabel.
Lead us to glory.
The first stone.
How I have dreamed of this moment.
And at last,
it has arrived.
Not quite.
You shouldn't have come, Clark.
Silly boy.
We owe you a debt
for revealing this chamber to us.
We were going to let you live.
I'm sorry, Lana, but I can't let you do this.
You don't have a choice.
Bear witness, Clark Kent,
to the dawn of a new age.
No!
His powers are restored.
How?
I'm not from around here.
It doesn't matter.
We took them from you once before.
Do you really believe that this time
will be any different?
I'm counting on it.
No!
Why are we lying in the dirt?
And what the hell are we wearing?
Are you okay?
Clark, what happened?
Well, let's just say that
you haven't been yourself lately.
Well, look who's finally here.
Mom, when did you guys get home?
This morning. Your dad is out there doing your chores.
Oh, sorry.
I guess I overslept.
Hey, Dad.
Hey, Clark.
Son,
is there maybe a little something
you'd like to tell your mother and me?
Where did that come from?
In the barn. In the hay.
Clark.
It was magic.
I'm sure it was.
No, I mean it really was.
Look, I should not have thrown this party without talking to you guys.
I know that.
But it's the way things spun out of control.
It was Lana. Well, it wasn't Lana exactly.
She was possessed by a witch
who then cast a spell on us and
that's how that happened.
Son, I realize that after all this is Smallville.
But witches and spells
and magic?
Dad, magic exists.
I saw it.
And worse, it can hurt me.
You lead quite a path of destruction.
Lex.
I'm sorry.
I was going to come see you.
Preemptive strike.
Just in case there was any evil dead action
still brewing.
Apparently I have been
exorcised.
I didn't do anything
to you, did I?
Nothing permanent,
but you did display some
intriguing abilities.
I don't remember anything.
I don't think I really want to.
I'm just glad you're all right.
Thanks to Clark.
I don't remember what he did,
but Isabel's back
to being history.
I guess we all owe Clark our gratitude.
Yeah.
You know,
I really don't understand him.
He can be
so selfless,
risking his life for his friends,
and then he turns around
and gets Jason fired.
Because what?
You know, he's jealous.
Lana.
Clark didn't
get Jason fired.
I did.
You what?
Look,
no matter how mature you may think
you are, the fact is you're still in high school,
and I wasn't going to
sit idle while someone in a position of authority
coerced you into a relationship.
What are you doing,
Lex?
I'm trying to protect you.
Do you really think that's what I need?
Lana,
I know you're upset,
but I only had your best interests
at heart.
My interests are none of your
concern, Lex.
I'm old enough to decide who
I want in my life,
and who I don't.
At least those aren't mine.
Hey, Lana.
I don't know your
I wanted to thank you.
Once again,
you managed to come to my rescue.
Well, it's good to have the old Lana back.
Isabel was, um,
aggressively sexy.
Oh, great.
Possessed by an evil slut.
Um,
I found out that Lex was the one that got
Jason fired.
I should have known that she would never do anything
like that.
I wasn't thrilled
when I heard about you and Jason.
But I realized that the way
I acted when we were together didn't make you
happy.
I always resented you for keeping secrets from me.
And I don't want to do the same
thing to you.
Clark,
there's a reason that I came back to Smallville.
When I was in Paris,
I touched Isabel's tomb, and then there was this
flash of light, and the next thing I remember
is waking up in my apartment.
And I had this.
I've seen this before.
On the cave wall.
I should have told you this months ago.
But I was too scared.
Clark, you know
those caves better than anyone else.
Do you know what this symbol means?
No.
I'm sorry.
What can I do for you to leave me alone?
What do you say to the ending for me to be
a connecting part of yours?
And if that's what you want...
Then it gets better.
Then we can be friends forever.
And that's for good.
I'm sorry, Clark.
I can't forgive you enough.
sí, de mi.
Blur dentes y cortes.
Thank you.